Erik Hirsch

Apple Valley, CA 92308
Phone: 760 420-4308 | Email: ehirsch760@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/e-hirsch | GitHub: github.com/eh4git

Portfolio: eh4git.github.io/React Profile

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with previous management experience and a passion for problem solving and collaboration. Effectively communicates with others to streamline the development cycle to produce polished applications. Known by peers for having a strong work ethic and being determined to produce the highest quality results possible.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6

Technologies: Node, React, React Native, Redux, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose,

Express, jQuery, BootStrap, Semantic, Materialize, Handlebars.js, Ajax, Sass

Projects

Once Upon An Adventure - July 2020

www.onceuaa.com | github.com/eh4git/once-upon-an-adventure

A collection of educational mini games within an RPG style browser game.

- Polished Bootstrap UI allows users to customize and control a character's movement.
- JavaScript and canvas html elements utilized in the creation of educational mini games.
- Integrates MongoDB to provide data persistence.
- Implemented React for the front end UI incorporating hooks and Redux to manage state.
- Node and Express used to create back end logic that handles Ajax requests.
- Secured user accounts implement bcrypt to hash and salt passwords.

Key Role(s): Animation of sprites, music, and sound effects

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Howler, Ajax, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Redux

Story Time - June 2020

github.com/eh4git/StoryTime | fathomless-waters-70908.herokuapp.com Personalized children's story generator.

- Responsive Bootstrap UI allows users to easily navigate while using the application.
- Developed front end logic using ¡Query.
- Integrates MongoDB to provide data persistence.
- Node and Express used to create back end logic that handles requests.
- Secured user accounts implement brrypt to hash and salt passwords.

Key Role(s): HTML, JavaScript, Front end logic

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query, Ajax, MongoDB, Express, Node

YouMDb - May 2020

github.com/eh4git/YouMDb-Movie-App | eh4git.github.io/YouMDb-Movie-App/ Movie information search and recommendations web application.

- Integrates local storage to provide data persistence.
- jQuery is used to make Ajax requests to APIs and render html.
- Implements iframe HTML elements to embed YouTube movie trailer videos.
- HTML layout utilizes Bootstrap to create a responsive web application.

Key Role(s): Bootstrap HTML layout and CSS

Technologies: Ajax, Express, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

Experience

Enumerator 2020 - Present

US Victorville, CA

- Strong communication skills used to engage and connect with the public.
- Work 100% independently to complete daily tasks.
- Responsibly handle sensitive materials to ensure privacy law requirements are met.

Delivery Driver 2019 - 2020 United Parcel Service Victorville, CA

- Worked independently while managing time efficiently.
- Recognized for strong work ethic.

Awarded by management for achieving highest performance on multiple occasions.

Project Manager

2015 - 2019

Rick Kittson Hardwood Flooring

Irvine, CA

- Supervised a small team to maintain quality and to complete projects in a timely manner.
- Recognized for strong work ethic.
- Provided training when necessary.
- Secured materials required to complete projects.

Cooling Operator

2017 - 2018

Golden Island

Rancho Cucamonga, CA

- Reduced labor costs by 50% through assisting in the implementation of new cooling systems and procedures.
- Attained recognition for excellent attendance record.

Education

UCLA Extension - Los Angeles, CA

Full Stack Web Development - Certificate

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.

Victor Valley College - Victorville, CA

Management Certificate of Completion - Certificate

31 Unit program that teaches the skills that are required for management. Courses included Accounting, Economics, Computer Literacy, Human Resource Management, Legal Environment of Business, Business Math, and Business Communications.